Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
Alan Sondheim Papers
1965-2010
Fales Library and Special Collections
Sondheim, Alan
MSS.267
55.5 Linear Feet in 21 record cartons, 47 manuscript boxes, 11 flat boxes, 3 media boxes, 1 LP box, 1 flat file, and 4 oversize film cans
88 sound tape reels
216 audiocassettes
47 film reels including 23 8mm film reels, 1 super 8 film reel, 22 16mm film reels, and 1 35mm film reel.
87 videoreels (1/2 inch)
100 videocassettes (u-matic)
7 videocassettes (betamax)
1 videocassettes (betacam)
124 videocassettes (vhs)
3 videocassettes (minidv)
87 videocassettes (hi8)
2 sound discs (vinyl)
260 Gigabytes in 30,768 digital files
Alan Sondheim (born 1943) is an author, musician, artist, and cyberspace theorist. His work explores embodiment in cyberspace and the use of computer technology and coding languages for personal and artistic expression. This collection contains Sondheim's intellectual and artistic work across many mediums. It includes his written work in articles, manuscripts, e-mails, and digital files; his visual artwork portrayed on paper and canvas, in photographs, photo slides, and negatives, and in digital images; his musical work, as both a solo artist and as a member of the groups Damaged Life and Ritual-All-7-70, on audio reels and audiocassettes; his work as a filmmaker on a variety of film and video formats; his engagement in exhibitions and performances, often in collaboration with other artists; and his academic career, reflected in lecture notes, instructional materials, and syllabi.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Alan Sondheim in April, 2010; the accession numbers associated with this collection are 2009-267 and 2023-043.
Appraisal
During processing an archivist identified published books, commercial audiovisual recordings, art pieces by other artists, and personal documents. These materials were removed from the collection, deaccessioned, and offered back to the donor by a curator in 2022.
During processing of the accretion associated with accession number 2023-043, 3 linear feet of materials were identified as outside of the scope of the collection and offered back to the donor. These materials included original housing, art pieces by other artists, and personal items.
Arrangement
Organized into six series:
Series I. Written Work
Series II. Visual Art
Series III. Musical Recordings
Series IV. Film and Video Recordings
Series V. Exhibitions and Events
Series VI. Academic Career.
Biographical Note
Alan Sondheim is an author, musician, artist, and cyberspace theorist. He was born February 3, 1943 in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania and received a B.A. and M.A. in English from Brown University.
Sondheim's work explores embodiment in cyberspace and Codework, which is the use of computer coding languages for creative expression. His written works include Being on Line: Net Subjectivity (1997), Disorders of the Real (1988), .echo (2001), Vel (Blazevox, 2004-5), Sophia (Writers Forum, 2004), The Wayward (2004), and Writing Under (2012), as well as numerous other chapbooks, ebooks, and articles. In 1994, Sondheim began a "continuous meditation on cyberspace" titled The Internet Text. This collection of writing and mixed media art is distributed via the email list "Cybermind" and displayed online (https://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/sondheim__internet_text.html). He has also co-moderated several email lists, including "Cyberculture," "Wryting," "Fiction of Philosophy," "Image," and "Deleuze World." Sondheim's writing is philosophical and poetic in nature, often incorporating computer coding languages and concepts from online gaming communities.
Sondheim is also a musician, and has released numerous albums as a solo musical artist and a member of the groups Damaged Life and Ritual-All-7-70. He started out as a guitarist, and expanded to playing a variety of instruments, including ghijak, cura, saz, sarangi, sing lisu, harmonica, and Chinese mouth harp. His music is characterized as post-industrial, avant-garde, and free improvisation. He frequently collaborates with his partner, singer/songwriter Azure Carter. Sondheim has also collaborated extensively with Swiss choreographer and dancer Foofwa d'Imobilité (Frederic Gafner), as well as many other dancers, often using tools like motion capturing technology to explore themes of embodiment and sexuality in cyberspace.
Sondheim has created several films and videos, including The Blue Tape (1974, co-directed with Kathy Acker), Hollywood (1981), Postmodern Pobre (1992), Nikuko (2000), and Trilby (2002). Much of his filmography includes digital avatars that are manipulated with 3D blending software. He has also shot a large collection of travel and nature photography and videography.
Sondheim has completed residencies at the trAce Online Writing Centre of Nottingham-Trent University, SecondLife's Odyssey exhibition space, West Virginia University's Center for Literary Computer and Virtual Environments Laboratory, and Grand Central Art Center in Santa Ana. In 2001-2002, Sondheim taught New Media at Florida International University in Miami. In 2006-2007, he taught filmmaking at his alma mater, Brown University. His mixed media art has been exhibited and performed internationally and across the United States. He also speaks at symposiums, conferences, and cultural events that explore cyberspace theory, including the Cybermind96 Conference, CyPosium, and South by Southwest.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
Alan Sondheim is an author, musician, artist, and cyberspace theorist. His work explores embodiment in cyberspace and the use of computer technology and coding languages for personal and artistic expression. This collection contains Sondheim's intellectual and artistic work across many mediums, including written work, visual art, films and videos, musical recordings, multimedia exhibitions, and dance performances.
Sondheim's work is primarily concerned with the convergence of the real world with the virtual world, expressed through artistic creation and collaboration. The written work in this collection ranges from calculator programs to philosophical academic texts and poetic reflections on virtual environments. Some written pieces include multimedia and web elements, and some are nestled within email listservs.
The musical recordings in this collection include Sondheim's solo work, as well as works by the bands Damaged Life and Ritual-All-7-70 (often referred to as "All"). These recordings are characterized as post-industrial, avant-garde, and free improvisation, and include a large variety of musical instruments. In addition to sound recordings, this collection also holds written documents pertaining to Sondheim's musical career, such as set lists, performance flyers, liner notes, and circuitry diagrams. There are also many photographs of Sondheim and his contemporaries capturing Very Low Frequency (VLF) recordings in natural settings.
The films, videos, and visual art in this collection iterate on the human body manipulated with technology, often with 3D blending programs, motion capture techniques, and modern dance. Codework, a concept created by Sondheim that refers to the use of computer coding languages and technology for creative expression, can be found throughout the collection. Sondheim's work frequently explores sexual themes, and may include sexually explicit content.
In addition to his solo work, Sondheim has worked with numerous artists. Throughout the collection, collaborative pieces with musician Azure Carter, choreographer and dancer Foofwa d'Imobilité, writers Kathy Acker and Sandy Bladwin, filmmaker Leslie Thornton, poet Miekal And, and many others highlight the collaborative nature of Sondheim's work.
Sondheim's films, exhibitions, and dance performances have premiered across the U.S. and internationally. He has held residencies at the trAce Online Writing Centre, SecondLife's Odyssey, West Virginia University's Center for Literary Computer and Virtual Environments Laboratory, and Grand Central Art Center in Santa Ana. Sondheim has taught New Media at Florida International University (2001-2002), Filmmaking at Brown University (2006-2007), and has been an Artist in Residence at many other institutions. He has also appeared at many symposiums, conferences, and cultural events, including the Cybermind96 Conference, CyPosium, and South by Southwest. Sondheim's travels greatly influence his work, and in addition to event documentation, this collection includes a large volume of photographs and videos related to travel.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Cyberspace -- Political aspects.; Art and the internet -- Exhibitions; Computer art.; Digital art; New media art.; Video art -- United States.; Experimental films -- United States; Slides (Photography); Gender identity -- United States; Feminist theory.
- Series I. Written Work, 24 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box.; 507 Megabytes in 6,369 digital files.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Written Work includes Alan Sondheim's intellectual and artistic writing in articles, manuscripts, e-mails, and digital files. His published works include Being on Line: Net Subjectivity (1997), Disorders of the Real (1988), .echo (2001), Vel (Blazevox, 2004-5), Sophia (Writers Forum, 2004), The Wayward (2004), and Writing Under (2012), as well as numerous other chapbooks, ebooks, and articles. In 1994, Sondheim began a "continuous meditation on cyberspace" titled The Internet Text This collection of writing and mixed media art is distributed via the email list "Cybermind" and displayed on his website. He has also co-moderated several email lists, including "Cyberculture," "Wryting," "Fiction of Philosophy," "Image," and "Deleuze World." Sondheim's writing is philosophical, poetic, and often sexual in nature. He frequently incorporates computer coding languages and concepts from online gaming communities in his work.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically. Wherever possible, record titles were taken directly from Sondheim's work.
  - "/ or Division", Undated; cuid35096 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "…", 1978; cuid35097 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - .echo, 2001; cuid36121 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_1)
  - "1A", Undated; cuid35098 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - "2/8/2200", Undated; cuid35099 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - "20th Century Art", Undated; cuid35100 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - "2nd Rate", Undated; cuid35101 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "2 sections", Undated; cuid35102 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - "3/4", Undated; cuid35103 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "3 Fires", Undated; cuid35104 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - "3 Pieces", Undated; cuid35105 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - "3 Times Latin", 1969; cuid35106 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - "11:00 News and the Problem of [M]", Undated; cuid35107 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - "The 14 Stations of the Cross", Undated; cuid35108 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - "100.", 1973; cuid35109 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - 911, 2001; cuid36122 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_2)
  - "A Book of Poems Lost", Undated; cuid35110 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - "Absolute Pleasure of Impenetrable Beauty of Joan and Tiffany", Undated; cuid35111 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - "Absurd", 1983; cuid35112 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - "Access and Regime", 1980; cuid35113 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - "The Accidental Tourist: Phenomenology of the Virtual", 2008; cuid36135 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_15)
  - "The Act of the Hand is the Manner of Speech", Undated; cuid35114 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - "A Face", Undated; cuid35115 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - "A Film for Characters", Undated; cuid35116 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - "Afterbirth", Undated; cuid35117 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - "After Madrid", 1990; cuid35118 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - "Against Love", Undated; cuid35119 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - "A Generalized Scheme for Open-Parameter Experimentation", Undated; cuid35120 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - "A Generation Which Circulates Around the Usual Limitations", Undated; cuid35121 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - "A Good Novel Gone Bad: A Short Evening Dwarf", Undated; cuid35122 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - "AIR", Undated; cuid35123 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - "Alan, Alan, Alan", Undated; cuid35124 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - "Alan Sondheim: Atlanta's Avant-Garde Woody Allen," Image, November 1984; cuid36111 (Box 77, Folder 25)
  - "Alan Sondheim: From Nexus to Texas," Image, August-September 1985; cuid36116 (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - "Alan Sondheim It Is the Name Alan Sondheim", Undated; cuid35125 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - "Alan Sondheim's Electric Guitar and Other Instrumentalities," Providence Sunday Journal, November 10 1968; cuid36109 (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - "A Legend", Undated; cuid35126 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - "A Little Bit of Subject Matter", Undated; cuid35127 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - "Alternate Current," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35128 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Alternate Interview (Transcribed), Undated; cuid35129 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - "(Alternative)," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35130 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - "A Manifesto", Undated; cuid35131 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - "A Memoir Of Madame Duren", Undated; cuid35132 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - "Americans and Others", 1980; cuid35133 (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - "Amino", 1971; cuid35134 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - "A Model for the Mathematical Relationships in the Self/World Dyad," Meta Ltd., 1973; cuid35135 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - "Analog/Digital" by Alan Sondheim with Sandy Baldwin, 2006; cuid35136 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - "Analyses of Language", Undated; cuid35137 (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - "Analysis/Descent", 1980; cuid35138 (Box 31, Folder 43)
  - "The Analysis of Situation", 1972; cuid35139 (Box 31, Folder 44)
  - "The Analysis of Situation: Subject Groupings", Undated; cuid35140 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  - "An American Game", Undated; cuid35141 (Box 31, Folder 46)
  - "An Augustan Exercise", Undated; cuid35142 (Box 31, Folder 47)
  - "…And Negation?", Undated; cuid35143 (Box 31, Folder 48)
  - "And the Poem", Undated; cuid35144 (Box 31, Folder 49)
  - "An Epitaph To a Lady Dressed in White", Undated; cuid35145 (Box 31, Folder 50)
  - "A New Brown Group" by Ron Roeschlaub, Brown Daily Herald, September 29 1967; cuid36115 (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - "Angelface", Undated; cuid35146 (Box 31, Folder 51)
  - "Angelina", Undated; cuid35147 (Box 31, Folder 52)
  - "Angelina and Sorrow", Undated; cuid35148 (Box 31, Folder 53)
  - "Animal", Undated; cuid35149 (Box 31, Folder 54)
  - "Annihilation", Undated; cuid35150 (Box 31, Folder 55)
  - "Annihilation: To the Limit!", Undated; cuid35151 (Box 31, Folder 56)
  - "An, Ode," Burning Deck, 1968; cuid35152 (Box 31, Folder 57)
  - "Anorexia", Undated; cuid35153 (Box 31, Folder 58)
  - "Anorexia/The Anorectic Real", Undated; cuid35154 (Box 31, Folder 59)
  - "Another Mother of Us All (A Phenomenology of Short-Wave)", Undated; cuid35155 (Box 31, Folder 60)
  - "Another One of These Readings", Undated; cuid35156 (Box 31, Folder 61)
  - "Answers to Questions Put by Luca Venturi," John Hilliard, 1974; cuid35157 (Box 31, Folder 62)
  - "Anti-Hiatus: The Essay On Clutter", 1982; cuid35158 (Box 31, Folder 63)
  - "Antarctic", 1982; cuid35159 (Box 31, Folder 64)
  - The Anthology of the Analog and Digital, Edited by Alan Sondheim and Sandy Baldwin, circa 2005; cuid36136 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_16)
  - "Antipodes", Undated; cuid35160 (Box 31, Folder 65)
  - "Antonioni", Undated; cuid35161 (Box 31, Folder 66)
  - "A Number (of Recent Texts and Addenda to 'The Structure of Reality')", 1977; cuid35162 (Box 31, Folder 67)
  - "The Anxious", Undated; cuid35163 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "Aphorisms", Undated; cuid35164 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - "Apocalypse", Undated; cuid35165 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - "A Poem With Direct Reference to the Poetic", Undated; cuid35166 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - "Apologia For a Lack of Style", Undated; cuid35167 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - "The Apparition", Undated; cuid35168 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - "Appearances and Conceptualizations", Undated; cuid35169 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - "Appearances of Consciousness in Formal Systems", Undated; cuid35170 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - "Appearance of Gender", 1985; cuid35171 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - "Appendix: Catastrophe Theory and the Butterfly Catastrophe", Undated; cuid35172 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "Appendix (From Criss-Cross Magazine, Modified)", Undated; cuid35173 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - "A Probably Sporadic Event", Undated; cuid35174 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "Argument", Undated; cuid35175 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - "Argus Piece", 1970; cuid35176 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - "Arithmetic of the Signifiers Which Disavow the Self", 1984; cuid35177 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - "Arousal Flag Cum Fetus Bible Death", Undated; cuid35178 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - "Art", Undated; cuid35179 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - "Art and Facticity: Series of Annotations Leading to a Statement", 1978; cuid35180 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - "Art and Language", Undated; cuid35181 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - "Art and Mathematics", Undated; cuid35182 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Art Communication Edition, 1977; cuid36120 (Box 77, Folder 34)
  - Art Communication Edition - "Strike," Volume Two, 1978; cuid36119 (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - "Articulation of the Photograph", Undated; cuid35183 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - "Artifacts", 1983; cuid35184 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - "Art, Labor, and the University", Undated; cuid35185 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - "A Series of Works Leading Into a Preliminary Investigation of Time (T), Multi-Channel Processing (MC), and Random Generation of Speech and Movement (RG)," Meta Ltd., 1972; cuid35186 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - "A Short List of the Characterizations of Ideology", 1980; cuid35187 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - "As If", Undated; cuid35188 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - "Aspects of Being and Becoming," Meta Ltd., Undated; cuid35189 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - "Aspects of Being S", Undated; cuid35190 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - "Assorted Notes About Music", 1970-1990; cuid35191 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - "A The A The", Undated; cuid35192 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - "A Theory of Culture", Undated; cuid35193 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - "Atlanta", 1983-1984; cuid35194 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - "Atlanta 1917", Undated; cuid35195 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - "Atlanta Downbeat… On the Prowl With the Hawk", Undated; cuid35196 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - "Atlantic Atlanta 2100", Undated; cuid35197 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - "At Night", Undated; cuid35198 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - "Attempt", Undated; cuid35199 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - "At This Point in Time/Boulevard", Undated; cuid35200 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - "The Attributes of an Unnamed Planets", Undated; cuid35201 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - "Authenticity/The Authentic", Undated; cuid35202 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - "Autobiographical Insight", Undated; cuid35203 (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Autobiographical Writing, 1997-2010; cuid36139 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_19)
  - "Autopornography", Undated; cuid35204 (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - "Autrui", 1980; cuid35205 (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - "A Zen Tale", Undated; cuid35206 (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - "Azure, Nature, Digital: Phenomenologies of the Analogic and Digital, Deep Language, Nature", 2009; cuid36123 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_3)
  - "Ballads of John Yoko", Undated; cuid35207 (Box 32, Folder 45)
  - "B.B.", Undated; cuid35208 (Box 32, Folder 46)
  - "Beacon and Interference", Undated; cuid35209 (Box 32, Folder 47)
  - "Because I Start…", Undated; cuid35210 (Box 32, Folder 48)
  - "Bedtime Conversation About the Dead", Undated; cuid35211 (Box 32, Folder 49)
  - ": (Before) the Presence of Sleep", Undated; cuid35212 (Box 32, Folder 50)
  - "Beginning and End", Undated; cuid35213 (Box 32, Folder 51)
  - "Being (s)", 1970; cuid35214 (Box 32, Folder 52)
  - "Being There", Undated; cuid35215 (Box 32, Folder 53)
  - "Between the Beauty of the Universe At Once and Those Nagging Doubts…", Undated; cuid35216 (Box 32, Folder 54)
  - "Biosphere Of the Artist", 1968; cuid35217 (Box 32, Folder 55)
  - "Birds", Undated; cuid35218 (Box 32, Folder 56)
  - "Blank Pages", Undated; cuid35219 (Box 32, Folder 57)
  - "Blockage", 1975; cuid35220 (Box 32, Folder 58)
  - "Blockage", Undated; cuid35221 (Box 32, Folder 59)
  - "Blues Adjective", Undated; cuid35222 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - "Bodies in the Tensor Fields", 1993; cuid35223 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - "The Book as System of Military Defense", 1974; cuid35224 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - "Border Creatures", Undated; cuid35225 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - "Breakdown: We Are the Body They Warned You Against", Undated; cuid35226 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "Broken Blossoms", Undated; cuid35227 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - "Broken Blossoms, Quality of", Undated; cuid35228 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - "Butte", Undated; cuid35229 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - "But What is the Situation of the Other", Undated; cuid35230 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - "Cadère in Memorium", Undated; cuid35231 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - "Cain", Undated; cuid35232 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - "Calculator Programs", Undated; cuid35233 (Box 33, Folder 12, 13)
  - "Campground", 1971; cuid35234 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - "Candido Velo", Undated; cuid35235 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - "Care", Undated; cuid35236 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - "Case Ending", Undated; cuid35237 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Case of the Real, 1998; cuid36124 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_267_ER_4)
  - "Cases of Negative Verification", Undated; cuid35238 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - "Catalog Documentation: Right-Hand Page", Undated; cuid35239 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - "Categories of Criticism", Undated; cuid35240 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - "Census", Undated; cuid35241 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - "Ceres", Undated; cuid35242 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - "The Chapbook Exhibition", 1989; cuid35243 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - "Characteristics of Acoustic Space", Undated; cuid35244 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - "Characteristics of Repetition", Undated; cuid35245 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - "Characteristics of the Core - Theoretical Subtext", Undated; cuid35246 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - "Characteristics of the Space of Commodities", Undated; cuid35247 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - "Characteristics of the Space of Industrialization", Undated; cuid35248 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - "The Characterizations of the Word", 1975; cuid35249 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - "Chatterton", Undated; cuid35250 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - "Chatterton" Notes, Undated; cuid35251 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - "Children's Educational Television Program", 1976; cuid35252 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - "Choral", Undated; cuid35253 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - "The Chosen", Undated; cuid35254 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - "Christ, in his Supplication of Mary Magdalene", Undated; cuid35255 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - "Christian", Undated; cuid35256 (Box 33, Folder 36)